Guide to the Stanford University, Libraries, Foreign Language and Area Collections, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Libraries, Foreign Language and Area Collections, records
1976-1999
SC0974
Stanford University. Libraries. Foreign Language and Area Collections.
12.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, 2000-2013.
Information about Access
Access: There is a minimum of five business days required for paging Peter Frank's records.
Access: Mary Jane Parrine's files are currently unprocessed and not available.
Scope and Contents note
Collection contains the files of Roberto G. Trujillo, curator for Mexican American collections, 1977-1996; Peter R. Frank, curator for Germanic collections, 1976-1990; Mary Jane Parrine, curator for French and Italian collections, 1979-1999; and Wojciech Zalewski, curator for Slavic and East European collections, circa 1970s-1999. Included are minutes, reports, grant files, correspondence, proposals, and other materials.
Access Terms
Frank, Peter R., 1924-; Parrine, Mary Jane.; Trujillo, Roberto G., 1951-; Zalewski, Wojciech, 1937-; Academic libraries--Collection development.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2000-137
  - Files of Roberto Trujillo, Curator for Mexican American collections
    Pulled for Restriction:
    Folder: Comic book theft 1994.
    Folder: Luis Leal correspondence etc. which includes purchase price.
    - Index to files (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AIS 3 year plans (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Heritage project / UC Berkeley (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Archive/Manuscript Deposit Agreements (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Asilomar Retreat 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sierra Camp Retreat 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Associates of SUL (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Arte Publico Press (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Brooks, Connie 1994-95 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Digital Image Technology at Stanford 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Digital Conservation Proposal 1993-95 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Collection Development Conoco Project Report 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Collection Development Program Retreat 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Automation Training Working Paper 1986-88 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Collection Development Retreat 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Collection Development Retreat 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Commission on Undergraduate Education, Report of the Subcommittee on Techniques and Technology in Teaching and Learning, May 9, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Connectivity (Green/Meyer) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Core vs. Discretionary services (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Electronic collections development and management 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Electronic Journal work group 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Electronic journals 1993-95 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Final Report Task Group on Electronic Journals January 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Electronic Journals Policy Issues, Latin America, 1993-94 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Electronic publishing 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Fideicomiso para la Cultura Mexico-EU (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Fideicomiso para la Cultura Mexico-EU – 1993 proposals (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Fideicomiso para la Cultura Mexico-EU - 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bibliotecas Estados Unidos (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Fund for Culture / Educational and Cultural Exchange (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Future of Area Studies Librarianship 1995-96 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Futures Document July 22, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Harvard Journal of Hispanic Policy 1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Harvard Library Bulletin – "American Library Resources for Latin American Studies" by William Vernon Jackson, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hilton, Ron, 1993-94 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Homepage [HASRG] (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Homepage [HASRG] texts (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - [Homepage] American Literary Studies (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - [Homepage] British Literary Studies (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Inter-University Program for Latino Research [IUP] Archives & Working Group 1993-94 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Inter-University Program for Latino Research [IUP] Archives & Working Group 1992-93 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Inter-University Program for Latino Research [IUP] Archives & Working Group 1992-93 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Inter-University Program for Latino Research (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - University of New Mexico Oral History Program (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - IUP Oral History prospectus 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - IUP Internet (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - iup-partners@lmrinet.gse.ucsb.edu (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Kerns, Charles (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Kodak Image Workshop (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Murieta, Joaquin (photocopy of source in French) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - SALALM 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - SALALM 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - SALALM 1988-1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - SALALM 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - SUL Agenda for 1984-1990; D. Weber list June 14, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - SUL Agenda 1984-1990: 3rd draft Oct. 24, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Library Cabinet Retreat July 19, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Administrative Planning Steering Committee 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Library Research and Information Skills Program (a.k.a. Information Proficiency June 1984 working papers) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Library Research and Information Skills Program (a.k.a. Information Proficiency June 1984: revision edited by Trujillo) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Stanford/UC Berkeley Cooperative Program 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - AAU Research Libraries Project – Final reports 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - FLAC collection evaluation project, 1986-88 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Collection evaluation project, 1982-84 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Academic Libraries in California – Policy statement draft, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Articles in progress – Chicano Librarianship, notes 1977-78 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - National colloquium on Chicano Academic Library & Information Services 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - National colloquium on Chicano Academic Library & Information Services 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Newsletter project (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - SU Chicano Library Guide [resource materials mostly] (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - SU Chicano Library Guide [resource materials mostly] (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Luis Leal materials (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Luis Leal Private Library: Mexico (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Luis Leal Private Library: Latin America (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Luis Leal Private Library: Spain (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - NEH Grant Application: documenting Latino Civil Rights History; MALDEF processing grant application, joint with Hunter College, June 1, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - NEH/NHPRC Grant applications for the MALDEF processing project, 1983-1995 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
    - NHPRC grant application (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - NHPRC miscellany (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - MALDEF grant miscellany (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - NEH Proposal: Processing of the Manuscript Collections about the Mexican-American Experience 1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Grant for processing Mexican American collections, miscellany (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - BORDERLINE: An Online Information Retrieval Service for Library Materials on the United States – Mexican Borderlands; UCLA NEH proposal, May 1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - NEH Digital Preservation grant application re: Ricardo Sanchez Papers, June 1, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Classics Seminar Library, 1984-85 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Digital preservation [Ricardo Sanchez Collection] (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Task Force on Hispanic Resources of the Commission on Preservation and Access, 1995-96 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Three Year Plans, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Unicorn Overview (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - UT-LANIC's Development and its Role in Latin American Studies, by Nint Lin, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Hector Calderon [re Chicano Literary Criticism in a Social Context National Conference, held at Stanford] 1987 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Sal Castro, 1968 Los Angeles High School Blowouts [photocopied clippings and other items] (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - SUL Chicano acquisitions newsletter (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Anheuser-Busch Co. – MALDEF processing funding (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Luis Leal, Private Library, Mexico—Supplement (rare), with correspondence (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Luis Leal - vita, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2000-270
  - Germanic Curator's Files
    - Descriptions of Collections (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - D. Weber. Directors (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Director of Collections (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Roberto Trujillo, Tony Angiletta (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Early German Periodicals (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Expensive Items 1976-1990 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Expensive Items 1976-1990 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Negative Decisions (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Research and Public Funds (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Questionnaires and Commentaries on the Collections (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - FLAC Curators – General (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - FLAC Development Policy (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - FLAC Collection Review (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Presentations (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Special Projects (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Special Funds and Donors (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Elfie, Natalie (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Buying Trips (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Students and Interns (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Shared Purchases with UC Berkeley (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Harrassowitz Approval Plan (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Harrassowitz Correspondence and Varia (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Dealers A-Z (FRG) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Dealers (GDR) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Dealers – Austria, Ch (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Other Dealers (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Publishers (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Societies, Memberships (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Acquisitions (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Archives (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Catalog (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Circulation (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Conservation (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Development (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Gifts and Exchange (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Other Departments (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Reference (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Serials (1990) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Special Collections 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - RLG/RLIN (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Conoco (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Art (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Cubberley (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Hoover (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Meyer/Media (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Music (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Tanner (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Sciences and Others (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - President, Provost, Dean (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - German Department General (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - German Studies Department Professors ( - Sept. 90) [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - German Studies Department Professors ( - Sept. 90) [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - History Department Professors (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - German Department Students Orals and Dissertations (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Visiting Professors (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Center for European Studies (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Other Departments (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Overseas Studies (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Overseas Studies (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Alumni Association (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - CRIS Austrian Chair (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - German Chair (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Swiss Chair (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Austrian Matters (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - German Matters (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Swiss Matters (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - European Matters (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Media (TV, Film) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Libraries, Archives (USA) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Western European Libraries and Specialists (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Libraries, Archives, Europe (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Libraries, Archives, Europe (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Libraries, Archives, Europe (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Universities and Institutes (USA) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Universities and Institutions, Europe (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Universities and Institutions, Europe (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Universities and Institutions of Africa, Asia, and Australia (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Societies (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Austrian Institute (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - D, Goethe Institute (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Swiss and Others (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Individual Persons (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Statistics (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Peter Frank (General) (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2013-081
  - Files of Wojciech Zalewski, Curator for Slavic and East European collections
    - Typology of Russian Post 1989 journals (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Reprints (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Background for Typology of Russian post 1989 journals (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bibliography Course (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Article Selection of Library Materials (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - V World Congress of Post-Soviet Studies, Warsaw, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - IREX (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Zalewski in Library Bulletins (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Polish organizations Book-People Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - [Cyryllic?] Russica (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Mikheeva, Ostroi, Kharlamov, Dzhigo, Kandel (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence Russia Varia, Also 2 letters Vilnius (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ethnic Panel (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Handbook: Publishing, Bibliography, Libraries, Archives in Russia in Eastern Europe. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Publishers (minor) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Russian Reviews (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Russians/Soviets in the Pacific (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Travel invitations (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Libraries in Europe's Post Communist Countries, Poland, Krakow, 1995 Aug 3-5 (Box 1, Folder 19)